hi I'm Bret curus and I just wanted to
film a quick video to show the way that
I teach back extensions because I don't
think there's a single video on YouTube
where anyone explains the correct way to
do it so this here is the 45° version I
also have the glute ham developer back
here which lets you do back extensions
from um a different angle where you're
where you're more parallel with the
floor but this is the 45° version and
because it's called a back extension the
way most people do it um they will kind
of keep their hips locked up and you'll
see all the motion here at the spine
this is lumbar flexion lumbar extension
th in this version she's using all
erector spinet and then her hamstrings
and glutes they're firing more as
stabilizers not as Prime movers um
another and that's not a good way to do
it unless you're trying to isolate those
muscles but a better way to do it is to
make the motion go at the hips now
here's another way that people do it
incorrectly they come down and maybe
they have tight hamstrings and they'll
round a little bit at the bottom so
they'll round here and then when they
come up they come up too high and see
how she's hyperextending her low back so
this is probably the most common way
you'll see them being done a lot of
people think you're supposed to feel it
in your low back so they'll really try
and you know actively isolate that area
um because it's called a back extension
but that can be harmful to the back over
time you know repeated flexion and
extension the safest way and the most
effective way to do it is to keep the
spine in neutral position and move all
at the hip joint so here um the way I
show it is so come down Carly and I just
tell clients kind of relax everything
here um shut everything down get a good
stretch in the hamstrings and then
Envision the glutes squeezing to pull
yourself up now sometimes they get like
a kyotic posture here and I'm okay with
that cuz she's using the glutes to pull
her up so um when when you do it this
way the glutes are just I mean you can
see them right here come around here um
you can see her glutes are just
squeezing super hard raising her up
she's also using a lot of hamstring but
also a lot of glute so that's the way I
teach it and um we also can hold on to
weight okay back up now um I'll show
um here's a version we just hold it
right
here beneath the neck and we can do it
that way but I mean the main thing I'm
looking for is the spine stays pretty
much in neutral and the hip extensors
are doing the work so that's the way I
teach back extensions it's a very
effective exercise it's not going to
hurt the spine you can do it for High
Reps Low Reps medium reps it's an
excellent exercise especially
considering that in my opinion it
teaches the glutes to do more of the
work not just the hamstrings so it helps
teach the glutes to become a prime a
primary hip extensor not a secondary hip
extensor okay that's all